Inventory of the Archibald Woods Papers 1777-1893, 1783-1846
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- G[eorge] Jackson, Clarksburg, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Moses Chaplin[e], Robert or Archable [Archibald] Woods and John Caldwell, Ohio County [Virginia] [West Virginia], 25 October 1800., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 303)
  Vouching for William Tate who wishes to buy land in Ohio County for an [inn or tavern?].
- David Cloyd, n.p., to Archibald Woods, Ohio County [Virginia] [West Virginia], 23 October 1800., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 304)
  Thanking Woods for his offer to sell land to Cloyd at a reduced price.
- Rawley Evans, Morgantown [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Archi[bal]d Woods, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 4 November 1800., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 305)
  Trying to find out when Woods will be going to the woods to survey.
- Ja[me]s Poage, n.p., to Archi[bald] Woods, Wheelin[g], Ohio County, [Virginia][West Virginia], 15 December 1800., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 306)
  Informing Woods that [?] Duvall. had saved Woods' land from being sold for taxes and giving family news.
- P. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Ann Wood[s] Wheeling, Ohio [County, Virginia] [West Virginia], 24 December 1800., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 307)
- Evan Gwynn, Alleghany County, [Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Ohio County, Virginia, 31 December 1800., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 308)
  Concerning a stolen horse.
- Jos[eph] Spencer, Vienna, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 15 January 1801., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 309)
  Concerning the claim of Jacob Beason to land.
- W[illia]m McClenechan, Richmon[d, Virginia] to Archabel [Archibald] Woods, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 19 January 1801., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 310)
  Asking Woods to pay taxes on McClenechan's land for him.
- Abr[aha]m Chapline, Mercer County, Kentucky, to Archibald Woods, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 31 January 1801., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 311)
  Criticizing Woods' dealings with him.
- John Andreas, n.p., to Arch[ibald] Woods, n.p., 11 February 1801., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 312)
  Encloses receipts for wheat and asks to be sent flour.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to John Caldwell, Wheelling [Wheeling, Virginia] [West Virginia], 15 February 1801., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 313)
  Demanding payment.
- Henry Jolly, n.p., to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling [Virginia] [West Virginia], 27 February 1801., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 314)
  Wanting to buy land.
- Martha [(Poage)] Woods, n.p., to son[-in-law], Henery [Henry] Walker, 14 March 1801., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 315)
  Concerning military land warrants and Robert Woods.
- Answer in lawsuit of Poage vs. Bradford in Court of Common Pleas of Washington County, Pennsylvania, 30 March 1801. (Folder 316)
- Agreement (witnessed by Thomas Bounds) between Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., and John Black, n.p., 2 April 1801., 1 page. DS. (Folder 317)
  For Black to put a shingle roof on Woods' barn.
- Agreement (witnessed by [?] Johnson) between Archi[bal]d Woods of Ohio County and David Johnson and Jacob Hamblin, 24 April 1801., 1 page. DS. (Folder 318)
  For Woods to lease Johnson and Hamblin land.
- Appointment (issued by Peter Tinsley, Clerk) of Garrat Darland and John Haggin, 10 June 1801., 1 page. DS. (Folder 319)
  To take depositions in lawsuit of Robert Poage vs. David Bradford in Virginia High Court of Chancery.
- Sam[ue]l McCraw, Richm[on]d,[Virginia], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 17 June 1801., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 320)
  Concerning a lawsuit he is handling for Woods.
- [J. Israel?], n.p., to Archab[al]d [Archibald] Woods, near Wheeling town, Virginia [West Virginia], 20 June 1801., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 321)
- Agreement between Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., and Joseph McCoy, n.p., 10 July 1801., 1 page. DS. (Folder 322)
  Concerning the location of land by military warrant.
- Ja[me]s Woods, Montgomery County, [Virginia], to Archibald [Archibald] Woods, Ohio County, near Whealing, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 25 July 1801., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 323)
  Concerning a court decision in High Court of Chancery in [Woods?] vs. Wilson and Todd vs. executors [of ?] in Botetourt County Court.
- Henry Walker, Botetourt County, [Virginia], to Arche[bal]d [Archibald] Woods, Ohio [County, Virginia] [West Virginia], 28 July 1801., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 324)
  States he has not moved yet, but there is a wagon road across the mountains to Fincastle. Is sending money owed to Woods but can not send all of it. Gives family news.
- Zach[aria]s A. Beatty, Stewbenville [Ohio], to Archibald Woods, near Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 1 August 1801., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 325)
  Stating he will be going to Alexandria and Washington [D.C.] and will carry out business for Woods.
- W[illia]m E. Wilson, Augusta, [County, Virginia] to Archi[bal]d Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 17 August 1801., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 326)
  Telling about his crops and expressing Federalist sentiments.
- Tho[ma]s Wilson,[Morgantown, Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Ohio [County, Virginia] [West Virginia], 22 August 1801., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 327)
  concerns an injunction and money owed to Wilson.
  Included ALS, Polly Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to [Ann (Poage) Woods], giving family news. 1 page.
- Rob[er]t Poage, n.p., to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County [Virginia] [West Virginia], 15 September 1801., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 328)
  Requesting [Ann (Poage)] Woods' right of dower in land purchased from Woods by [?] McNear.
- A. Faw, Alexandria, [Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 22 September 1801., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 329)
  Requesting deeds.
- Nassam Dean, n.p., to [Archibald] Woods, n.p., 9 November 1801., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 330)
  Announcing his intention to move.
- Deposition taken by Garret Darland and John Haggin of Anne McGinty, Mercer County Kentucky taken in the lawsuit of Robert Pogue vs. David Bradford in the Virginia High Court of Chancery, 10 November 1801., 1 page. DS. (Folder 331)
- W[illia]m Downey, Gurnsey [Guernsey] County, Ohio, to Archibel [Archibald] Woods, n.p., 13 November 1801., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 332)
  Concerning David Yeates, a weaver.
- Robert Poage, n.p., to [Archibald] Woods, n.p., December [1801]., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 333)
  Concerning the deposition of [Thomas] Kenton in a land dispute and mentions [Henry] Lee.
- Robert Pogue, Maya Lick, [?], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling [West Virginia], 9 December 1801., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 334)
  Concerning a land dispute and the deposition of his mother Ann McGintry.
- Dan[iel] Call, Richmond, [Virginia], to Archibald Wood[s], Wheeling, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia] concerning Poage vs. Chapline[and Bradford.] 9 December 1801., 5 items. (Folder 335)
  Includes memorandum, n.d., concerning procedure in the lawsuit.
  Also includes memorandum 6 December 1797, of Archibald Woods, concerning Abraham Chapline, advice, 12 December 1797, of Bushrod Washington; cover sheet, 22 July 1801. of L. Burfoot, sending letter of Daniel Call; and copy (made by P. Tinsley) of decree 28 September 1805, of the Virginia Superior Court of Chancery in the lawsuit of Robert Poage vs. Abraham Chaplaine and David Bradford.
- John Poage, Chilicothy [Chillicothe, Ohio] to Arch[ibal]d Wood[s], Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 2 December 1801., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 336)
  Concerning military land disputes.
- Sam[ue]l McCraw, Richmond, [Virginia], to Archibald Woods, Wheelling, [Wheeling], Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 29 December 1801., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 337)
  Concerns a lawsuit between [?] McIntire and Archibald Woods and the debate in the General Assembly over the division of Kanawha County.
- Includes Alexander White, Philadelphia, [Pennsylvania] to [Archibald Woods], [1802?]., 4 pages. AMs. (Folder 338)
  concerning the Land Office bill.
  ALS. Deposition, 1802, of Archibald Woods in a land dispute.
- Agreement (witnessed by W[illia]m McConnell) between Woods, Ohio County, Virginia and Jacob Hambler and George Witt of the Northwestern Territory, 23 January 1802., 2 pages. DS. (Folder 339)
  For Woods to thirty-five acres to Hamblin and Witt. Hambler and Witt are to plant apple trees.
- John Buchanan, n.p., to Archibald Woods, n.p., 28 January 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 340)
  Concerning money owed to Woods.
- Agreement(witnessed by John White) between Archi[bal]d Woods, of Ohio County, Virginia, [West Virginia], and Massy [Massam] Dean of Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 15 February 1802., 3 pages. DS. (Folder 341)
  For Woods to lease ninety acres of land to Dean. Dean is to take care of orchard.
- Tho[ma]s Wilson, Morgantown, [West Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Ohio [County, Virginia] [West Virginia], 21 February 1802., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 342)
  Concerning military land warrants. Asks if Whetsel [Wetzel] got his money "for the Negro he sent down the River."
- G[eorge] Jackson, Washington, [D.C.], to Archibald [Archibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 12 March 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 343)
  Concerning [Albert] Gallatin and the Northwest Territory.
- Agreement (witnessed by Betsy Woods) between Archi[bal]d Woods of Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia] and Elijah Johnson of Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 23 March 1802., 2 pages. DS. (Folder 344)
  For Woods to lease to Johnson twenty-nine acres of land. Johnson is to take care of the fruit trees.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to [Joseph Tomblingson, n.p.,], 29 March 1802. (Folder 345)
  To change an agreement concerning the delivery of flour.
- Sam[ue]l McCraw, Richmond, [Virginia] to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 1 April 1802., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 346)
  Concerning the lawsuit of McIntire vs. Woods in the Virginia High Court of Chancery.
- Edw[ard] Bryson, Captena [Captina, Belmont County, Ohio], to Archebald [Archibald] Woods, Ohio County, Wheling [Wheeling, Virginia] [West Virginia], 12 May 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 347)
  Concerning land and the appointment of a magistrate.
- Petition of inhabitants of [Northwest Territory, later Belmont County, Ohio], 31 May 1802., 1 page. Copy of DS. (Folder 348)
  Concerning the appointment of a magistrate.
- Samuel H. Smith, Washington, [D.C.], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 15 July 1802., 1 page. PLS. (Folder 348A)
  Woods owes money for a subscription to Universal Gazette, a newspaper.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, Wheelling, [Wheeling, Virginia], to Will[ia]m Galaspy, n.p., 29 July 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 349)
- A[braham] Faw, Alexandria, [Virginia], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, [Ohio County, Virginia] [West Virginia], 16 August 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 350)
- Henry Moore, n.p., to Archibald Woods, near Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 8 September 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 351)
  Concerning land for Abraham Faw.
- Moses Chapline, Lieu[tenan]t Col[onel] Com[man]d[in]g, 4th Regiment, Virginia Militia, to Archibald Woods, Major, First Battalion, 4th Regiment, Virginia Militia, 8 September 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 352)
  Ordering him to order all commissioned officers to meet at Wheeling for muster and training.
- Ambros Creain and Steven Bowyer, Rockbridg[e] County,[Virginia], to Archabald [Archibald] Woods, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 27 October 1802., 1 page. LS. (Folder 353)
  Creain is interested in purchasing land from Woods and Bowyer would like to rent some land.
- Abr[a]m Chapline, Mercer County, [Kentucky], to Archibald Woods, Ohio County, Virginia, [West Virginia], 29 October 1802., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 354)
  Concerning money owed to Woods by Chapline.
  Includes Copy of ALS, n.d., of W[illia]m Gelaspie, Station Camp, Sumner County, Tennessee, to [Abraham Chapline], concerning money. 1 page.
- Zach[aria]s A. Beatty, Charlestown [West Virginia], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, [West Virginia], 30 October 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 355)
  Concerning [?] Biggs' surveying.
- Elnathan Scofield, Beilmont [Belmont] County, [Ohio], to Archibald Woods, 8 November 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 356)
  Concerning the surveying of land in the Northwest Territory.
- Stephan Bowyer, n.p., to Archabald [Archibald] Woodes [Woods], Ohio County [Virginia] [West Virginia], 9 November 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 357)
  Asking Woods to let Mark Jeacobs [Jacobs] live on land owned by Woods.
- George Slaughter [Paris, Kentucky], to Archibald Woods, Ohio County, near Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 17 November 1802., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 358)
  Requesting Woods to sell his land and it he has done so to remit payments in pot metal.
- Levi Boone, Maysville, [Kentucky], to Archibald Woods, Lexington, [Kentucky], 8 December 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 359)
  Decides not to exchange land with Woods.
- W[illiam] Croghan, near Louisville, Kentucky, to Archabald [Archibald] Woods, near Wheeling, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia]. (Folder 360)
  Has paid the tax on Woods' land to prevent sale for non-payment of taxes. Asks about worth of land he owns on Ohio River so he can sell or exchange it.
- A[nn (Poage)] Woods, n.p., to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Lexington, Ken[tuck]y, 13 December 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 361)
  Giving news about his mill.
- And[re]w Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Lexington, Kentucky, 14 December 1802., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 362)
  Concerning deed to land.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, Frankfort, [Kentucky], to William Crogan, Jefferson County, [Kentucky], 15 December 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 363)
  Thanking him for paying taxes on Woods' land.
- Joseph Woods, Eddyville, [Kentucky], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Lexington, Kentucky, 20 December 1802., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 364)
  Giving a description of Countyside. Joseph Woods is keeping a store. Gives price of flour.
- W[illia]m Wilson, n.p., to Arch[ibal]d Woods, near Wheeling [Virginia] [West Virginia], 30 December 1802., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 365)
  informing Ann Woods of death of her father and the division of his estate.
  Includes, ALS, E. Wilson, n.p., to sisister [sister, Ann (Poage) Woods], concerning the death of their father and giving other family news. 1 page.
- Agreement (witnessed by Robert Stewart) between Archi[bal]d Woods of Ohio County, Virginia and Levin Okey of Belmont County, Ohio, 26 January 1803., 2 pages. DS. (Folder 366)
  For Okey to lease thirty acres of land adjoining Captuna [Captina] Creek.
- John White, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 5 February 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 367)
  Concerning the milling of flour.
- Edw[ard] Bryson, Captena [Belmont County, Ohio] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling [Virginia] [West Virginia], 10 February 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 368)
  Concerning location of a salt spring and asking Woods to survey some land.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to Thomas Bounds, n.p., 16 February 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 369)
  Offering to exchange some land with him.
- Rob[er]t Woods, n.p., to Archi[bald] Woods,25 February 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 370)
  Concerning a plot for David Hozack's land.
- Sam[ue]l Smith, Whe[e]ling, Virginia [West Virginia], to Archi[bald] Woods, near Whe[e]ling, Virginia, 1 March 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 371)
  Concerning money owed to Woods for flour.
- Levin Okey, n.p., to Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., 5 March 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 372)
  Concerning the location of a court house in Belmont, County, Ohio and land.
- Agreement (witnessed by William [?] and Geo[rge] Knox) between Archi[bal]d Woods of Ohio County, Virginia and George Witt and Daniel Roberts of Belmont County, [Ohio], 15 March 1803., 2 pages. DS. (Folder 373)
  For Witt and Roberts to lease land in Belmont County, Ohio. Witt and Roberts are to preserve the orchard.
- Jo[seph] Woods, Eddyville, Kentucky, to uncle, Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 18 March 1803., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 374)
  Concerning money owed Archibald Woods. Discusses the murder of an Indian trader.
- Josiah Chapline & County, [Wheeling, Virginia?] [West Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 18 March 1803., 1 page. LS. (Folder 375)
  Requesting planks.
- Jacob Brock, n.p., to Archabel [Archibald] Woods, near Whealon, [Wheeling, Virginia] [West Virginia], 22 March 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 376)
  Wanting to lease land from Woods.
- Moses Chapline, Lieu[tenan]t Col[one]l Com[man]ding], of the 4th Regiment of the Virginia Militia, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Arche[i]bald Woods, [Wheeling, Virginia] [West Virginia], 5 April 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 377)
  Ordering him to order his battalion to report for training.
- John Nixon, n.p., to Archabald [Archibald] Woods, 14 April 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 378)
  Is sending his wife to pay Woods.
- Noah Linsley, n.p., to A[rchibald] Woods,15 April 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 379)
  Concerning a survey order.
- Sally Galbreth, Point Pleasant [Virginia] [West Virginia], to John Galbreth, Steubenville, Jefferson County, Ohio, 17 April 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 380)
  Concerning her arrival and health and Jane [?].
- Ja[me]s Neilson, Washington, Mississippi, Territory, to Arch[iba]ld Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 1 May 1803., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 381)
  Concerning politics in Mississippi, French in New Orleans and price of goods is Natchez.
- Joseph Tomlinson, Grave Creek, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Archabald [Archibald] Wood[s], n.p., 3 May 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 382)
  Concerning the settlement of a debt between Spencer and Sam[ue]l Biddle.
- A[ndrew] Woods, Jr., Eddyville, [Kentucky], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 1 May 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 383)
  Mentioning his poverty.
- John Brown, Boone County, Kentucky, to Archelus [Archibald] Wood[s], Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 31 May 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 384)
  Concerning military warrant land.
- M. M., Philad[elphi]a, [Pennsylvania], to John Wilson for Maria McKean, Washington, Pennsylvania, 6 May 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 385)
  Saying how much she is missed.
- E. Vaughan, Chillicothe, [Ohio], to Archibald W[oods], near Wheeling, Virginia, [West Virginia], 9 May 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 386)
  Inquiring about military land located for [?] Page.
- Jeremiah Hunt, Cincinnati, [Ohio], to Archibald Wood[s], Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 15 May 1803., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 387)
  Concerning the Ohio legislature and the location of the courthouse of [Belmont County, Ohio], the necessity of building a road to it, ferries and the Miami Exporting Company. [Bears notes in another hand] incomplete.
- Ja[me]s Poage, n.p., to Archibald Woods, Wheelin[g, Virginia][West Virginia], 2 June 1803., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 388)
  Discusses [Richard] Yeates' land and family news.
- W[illia]m [Perrine?], Wheelin[g, Virginia][West Virginia], to Archabald [Archibald] Woods, n.p., 3 June 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 389)
  concerning a survey.
- John Thomas, Mercer County, [Kentucky], to Archibald Woods, near Wheelin[g], Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 12 June 1803., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 390)
  Concerning title to land owned by [?] Graham.
- John Coalter, Staunton, [Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, n.p., 7 July 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 391)
  Telling Woods, Poage vs. Bradford & Chaplin[e] could not be tried in his district of the [Virginia High Court of Chancery].
- Archi[bal]d Woods, Wheelling [Wheeling, Virginia] [West Virginia], to Jon Smith, n.p., 22 July 1803., 1 page. copy of ALS. (Folder 392)
  Concerning a law suit and a possible exchange of land.
- Sam[ue]l McCraw, Richmond, [Virginia], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 27 August 1803., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 393)
  Concerning the lawsuit of McIntire vs. Woods in the Virginia High Court of Chancery. Gives his opinion of the Louisiana Purchase.
- Tho[ma]s Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to A[rchibald] Woods, Ohio [County, Virginia] [West Virginia], 20 September 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 394)
  Concerning the building of a dam.
- Catherine Johnston, n.p., to Archibald Woods, Ohio County within a few miles of Wheelan Town, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 22 September 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 395)
  Concerning land in Ohio County surveyed by Woods for her husband.
- George Slaughter, Bourbon [County], Kentucky, to Archibal[d] Woods, Ohio County, Virginia, 2 December 1803., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 396)
  Asking if Woods has sold his land for him. If so, please remit money in metal caskings.
- Jo[esph] Woods, Eddyville [Kentucky] to uncle A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 4 December 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 397)
  Saying he has sent Andrew [Woods] and an Indian trader up White River.
- Joseph Spencer, Vienna, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Moses Chaplin[e], Wheeling, Clerk Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 15 December 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 398)
  Concerning land.
- Mich[ae?]l Cresap, Grove Creek, [?] to Archibald Woods, near Wheelin[g, Virginia][West Virginia], 19 December 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 399)
  Asking Woods to come make a survey.
- E[lijah] Woods, n.p., to Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., [1804?]., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 400)
  Concerning money owed Woods by [Joseph?] Tomlingson.
- E[lizabeth?] Woods, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to [?], [1804]. (Folder 401)
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to [Robert] Pogue, n.p., 2 January 1804., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 402)
  Concerning disputed land in Kentucky.
- Agreement between Archi[bal]d Woods of Ohio County, Virginia and Robert Prittyman of Ohio County, Virginia, 15 January 1804., 2 pages. DS. (Folder 403)
  For Prittyman to lease land. Lease extended for another year.
- A[rchibal]d Woods, Wheling [Wheeling, Virginia] [West Virginia] to Richard Yates [Yeates], Kentucky, 18 January 1804., 1 page. ACy of ALS. (Folder 404)
  Concerning land disputes between Woods and Yeates.
- Note (witnessed by Joseph Cravens) from Lewis Collins to William Thompson, 17 February 1804. (Folder 405)
  For money received.
- W[illia]m Wilson, Augusta [County, Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 25 February 1804., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 406)
  Gives his opinions of Methodists.
- James McDowell, [Fairfield, Rockbridge County, Virginia], to [Archibald] Woods, 28 February 1804., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 407)
  Wants to exchange land with Woods.
- Agreement (witnessed by Moses Chapline and Josiah Chapline) between Denis Cassat of Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia] and Archi[bal]d Woods of Wheelling Creek [Ohio County, Virginia] [West Virginia], 20 March 1804., 2 pages. DS. (Folder 408)
  For Cassat to pay Woods back for flour.
- Polly Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Mrs. Ann Woods, Ohio [County, Virginia] [West Virginia], 23 March 1804., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 409)
- Dan[iel] Call, Richmond, [Virginia] to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County [West Virginia], 2 April 1804., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 410)
  Concerning the lawsuit of Poage vs. Chapline.
- George Madison, Frankfort [Kentucky], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling [West Virginia], 9 April 1804., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 411)
  Concerning [William] Croghan and land belonging to Woods in Kentucky.
- W[illiam] Croghan, near Louisville, Kentucky, to Archibald Woods, near Wheelling [Wheeling], Virginia [West Virginia], 18 April 1804., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 412)
  Concerning Croghan's purchase of land owned by Woods.
- Tho[ma]s Wilson, Morgantown, [West Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Ohio C[oun]ty, Virginia [West Virginia], 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 413)
  Concerning death of Aggy Poage, other family news and election of Philip Doddridge.